

# Rian Arthur Rutherford

Email - rianrutherford@outlook.com LinkedIn Portfolio Website

### About Me

Languages - English | Specialisation - Unreal Engine | Country - England, UK

Graduate Unreal Engine 5 C++ programmer, started coding in 2017. I have released 10 small games on itch.io over 3 years from 2022-2024 inclusive (<u>itch profile page</u>).

I want to work towards becoming a networking specialist for multiplayer games because I want to work on potential successors to games like Planetside 2. To improve my knowledge and experience with netcode for games, I recently started a side project in Godot 4 and Rust called <a href="Arcade">Arcade</a>. It's a multiplayer, 3rd person, spaceship, PvP game.

#### Education

BA(Hons) Game Development: Programming

Falmouth University, England; 2021 - 2024

Level 3 Computing BTEC Extended Diploma

Weston College, England; 2019 - 2021

## Work Experience

Blockception: Nov 2017 - Nov 2022

Freelance programmer at Blockception making Minecraft Maps.

Made: The Moa'ul Mountain, Dragon's Tale, and Mountain Retreat.

Weston Place Agency: Sept 2020 - May 2021

Website design team leader at Weston Place Agency. Responsibility: manage design team and website production.

Oracle Falls: Jan 2017 - Aug 2017

Credited volunteer game tester on Oracle Falls by Evil Robot Empire.

#### Interests

I like playing Dungeons & Dragons, watching anime, and occasionally playing video games; RTS and MMO are my favorite game genres.

Most recently I enjoyed playing Helldivers 2, Homeworld: Deserts of Kharak, and Higan: Eruthyll.

Some of my favorite animes are: The Misfit of Demon King Academy, Gate, and BOFURI.

### Skills

#### **Programming Languages**

C++ | Rust | Blueprints | Python | GDScript | C#

#### **Game Engines**

Unreal Engine | Godot | Unity | Bevy

## Projects

Swamp Fell: Sept 2023 - May 2023

3D game with action combat and questing, made in Unreal Engine 5. Team of eight. Worked on modular health component, enemy AI, and quest system.

Wrong Turn at...Convention: Dec 2023

2D roguelike made using <u>Bevy</u> and Rust for a game jam. I made the AI and camera controller. Video by team member here.

Cyberturn: Sept 2022 - May 2023

Team of six. Turn-based game made in Unreal Engine 5. Core systems programmer: worked on AI and tile movement system.

Demise: Dec 2022

Multiplayer game made in Unreal Engine 5 in one week. Worked as a solo developer.

Sentinel: Jan 2022

2D game made in Godot 3 for a game jam, uses 3rd party assets. Worked as a solo developer.

LANSpace: Oct 2021

Multiplayer 2D game made using Python 3 and PyGame. Worked as a solo developer.